(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-15T22:59:49.379126",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
らんらんらん...
Ran, ran, ran...
我儘姫
[Selfish Princess]
ワンツースリー 不思議なステップで踊ろう
One, two, three, let's dance with mysterious steps!
響きだすビート 今宵輝く夜空の下で光る
An echoing beat, shining under tonight's sparkling night sky!
私可愛い可愛い召使い達 あの子はどこに？
I'm cute, cute... Servants, where is that child?
うだうだ ぐだぐだ だらだら にゃんにゃんにゃんにゃんにゃん 何でもおっしゃる通り
Uda-uda, guda-guda, dara-dara, nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan, everything as you command!
甘い甘いチョコが食べたい
I want to eat sweet, sweet chocolate,
熱い熱いラテが飲みたい
I want to drink hot, hot latte,
ほくほくのパン食べたいの ダメ？
I want to eat warm, fluffy bread. Is that a no?
とろとろのチーズが食べたい
I want to eat gooey, melted cheese,
ふかふかのベッドで寝たい
I want to sleep on a fluffy, soft bed,
うとうとおやすみなさい
Dozing off... Good night.
スッピー
Sleepy...
わがまま
Selfish!
らんらんらん 誰も逆らわないで
Ran, ran, ran, nobody disobey me!
わがままは愛の印でしょ
Being selfish is a sign of love, right?
お願い ギブ ギブ プリーズ 全て集めて
Please, give, give, please, gather everything
私に捧げて 何でもかんでも許される
and dedicate it to me, anything and everything is forgiven!
だって私が一番可愛いから
Because I'm the most cute, after all!
スリーツーワン 香ばしい匂いに誘われだすビート
Three, two, one, led by a fragrant aroma, the beat starts!
今宵月明かりの下で誰と踊る？
With whom shall I dance under the moonlight tonight?
キャロットジュース 火あぶりステーキ お好きなオプションで
Carrot juice, roasted steak, with your favorite choices!
誰も私には勝てない いつまで経っても終わらない
Nobody can win against me, it will never end, no matter what!
苦い苦いピーマン食べたい
I want to eat bitter, bitter green pepper,
赤い赤いスープ飲みたい
I want to drink red, red soup,
コプコプお肉食べたいの ダメ？
I want to eat delicious meat. Is that a no?
甘い甘いこれじゃ足りない
Sweet, sweet, this is not enough!
油断したフェイスまた見せて
Show me your off-guard face again.
らららら らららら
La la la la, la la la la...
ほらまだまだ終わらないわ
Look, it's not over yet!
わがまま ねえ私のこと愛してくれる？
Selfish... Hey, will you love me?
誰かを待っているの
Are you waiting for someone?
孤独な夜空に一人 窓から覗いて
Alone in the lonely night sky, looking out the window...
お星様も踊ってる
Even the stars are dancing,
だって私が わがまま
because I'm selfish.
ランタッタッタッタッタリン
Ran-ta-ta-ta-ta-rin!
怖がらないで お茶時間は急ぐでしょ？
Don't be afraid, teatime is running out, right?
お願い ギブギブミー
Please, give, give me...
すべて与え続けて 何もかも許される
Keep giving me everything, and all will be forgiven.
やっぱ私が一番可愛いんだから
After all, I'm the cutest!
Myth or Treat
Trick or treat
キミの推しはクローゼットの中でドッキリを仕掛けた
Your favorite set up a prank inside the closet.
TRICK or TREAT ほら もうキャンディーはない
Trick or Treat, look, there is no more candy.
お腹がいっぱい？じゃあ、チェーンソーの出番かな？
Are you full? Then is it time for the chainsaw?
みんなが取り憑かれた
Everyone has been possessed.
その仮説を確かめよう 解剖しよう
Let's test that hypothesis. Let's dissect you.
踊れ 隠れないで泣き虫
Dance, don't hide, you crybaby.
幻想のない HALLOWEEN は面白くない Haha
A Halloween without illusions is no fun, haha.
みんなが手招いている
Everyone is beckoning you.
かわいい
Cute...
熱くなった血を
Will you give us...
くれるでしょう？
your hot blood?
Myth or Treat
あぁ 呪いの配信
Ah, a cursed stream.
びびって叫んじゃえ！
Get scared and scream!
見せるよ今夜だけ
We'll show you, only for tonight,
まだ見ぬ恐ろしい顔を
a terrifying face you've never seen.
あぁ なんてガチ恋 NIGHT
Ah, what a deeply-in-love night.
魔女たちの出番だ
It's time for the witches' debut.
もう逃げられないよ
You can't escape anymore.
捧げて君の魂を
Surrender your soul.
踊りだせ TONIGHT
Start dancing tonight.
見て 恐ろしい SIGHT
Look at this terrifying sight.
腹ペコだ、食べたいねぇ、ちょうだい？
I'm starving, I want to eat, won't you give me some?
恐怖でびびらせ 一緒に歌おう
Scaring you with fright, let's sing together.
「嫁」じゃなくてかぼちゃ DING-DONG?
Not a "wife", but a pumpkin DING-DONG?
墓場で待ってる 覚悟できてる？
Waiting in the graveyard, are you prepared?
我らの歌で盛り上がるがいい！
You'd better get hyped up by our song!
べー、ふふっ
Bleh! *giggle*
おびえて叫べ！
Be terrified and scream!
MYTHが暴れる これぞ我らのスタイル
MYTH runs wild, this is our style!
イェーイ！
Yay!
イェイイェーイ！
Yay, yay!
やったー！楽しかったー！
We did it! That was so fun!
いや、すごかった
Wow, that was amazing!
いい曲だったねー
It was a great song!
楽しかったー！
It was so fun!
Calliちゃん達とこの曲歌えるのめちゃ嬉しい
I'm so happy to sing this song with Calli and everyone!
うん、うん
Yeah, yeah.
あ、私も3Dで踊りたいよー！
Ah, I want to dance in 3D too!
えー、見たいー！
Aw, I want to see that!
踊りたいです！私も3Dで早く見たい！
I want to dance! I want to see myself in 3D soon too!
ね、見たいよねー
Right? We want to see it too.
いつになるのー？
When will it happen?
わかんなーい！
I don't know!
わかんないけど楽しみに待っててー
I don't know, but please look forward to it!
待ってるよー！
We're waiting!
でもなんか、今日2Dだけど、いい感じに後ろにさ、ね？
But even though we're in 2D today, we're nicely placed in the background, right?
確かに、うん、確かに
True, yeah, indeed.
画面がすごい、うん
The screen is amazing, yeah.
デカい！
Gigantic!
デカいね、私たち
We're huge, aren't we?
一緒に歌えてよかった
I'm glad we could sing together.
ねー、そうだね
Yeah, that's true.
巨人
Giants.
あ、すごい、このMyth or TreatはもともとENのみんなで英語で歌った曲だったんだけど
Wow, amazing. This song, Myth or Treat, was originally sung in English by EN, but...
日本語でまさか歌えるなんて思ってなかったです。嬉しい。
I never thought we would sing it in Japanese. I'm so happy.
うん！メルもこの曲さ、聞いたときからめっちゃ大好きな曲だったから、嬉しいよ！
Yeah! Mel has loved this song ever since I first heard it, so I'm so glad!
わー、よかった！
Aww, I'm glad!
いや日本語版すごいいい感じに聞こえて、すごく歌いやすかったです。すごかった。
No, the Japanese version sounded really natural and was very easy to sing. It was amazing.
本当？そう、結構自分でね、これやったら可愛いかな？っていう風に、ちょっと直してみた。
Really? Yeah, I actually tweaked it myself, thinking, "Would this sound cuter if I did it this way?"
おおー！すごーい！
Ooh! Amazing!
自分で？すごーい！
By yourself? Incredible!
メル様のこの誕生日に歌うっていうのもね、なかなかじゃないですか？
And singing this on Mel-sama's birthday is quite special, isn't it?
おー、嬉しい！やっぱハロウィンだからさ、ぴったりだよね、この曲ね
Aw, I'm happy! Since it's Halloween, this song is perfect, right?
ね、ハロウィン、うん、うん
Yeah, Halloween, yeah, yeah.
いやもう、メル様、お誕生日おめでとう！
Anyway, Mel-sama, happy birthday!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy birthday!
おめでとうー！
Congratulations!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
ハッピーバースデー！
Happy birthday!
この後も色々あるんじゃないですか？
Isn't there more coming up after this?
そうなんだよ、まだ2曲目だからさ、まだまだ歌うんだけど
That's right, this is only the second song, so we're going to keep singing more...
え、待って...
Wait...
え、なんか、帰る感じ？
Oh, are you leaving already?
いやー！
No way!
違うよ。ハロウィンだから魔界の住人たちを...
No, since it's Halloween, we have to go...
お菓子いっぱいもらいに行かないといけないんです！
...get lots of treats from the underworld residents!
うわー
Wow!
え、ちょっと待って！魔界のチョコ？お腹空いた！
Wait! Underworld chocolate? I'm hungry!
あ、分かる！お腹空いた！
Oh, I get it! I'm hungry!
食べにいっちゃう？食べにいっちゃう？
Should we go eat? Should we go eat?
ちょっと待って！私も行きたい！
Wait! I want to go too!
いっぱいある、いっぱいある！ちょっと待って！
There's tons of it, tons! Wait, wait!
ねえ、ずるい！勝手に食べないで！待って！
Hey, no fair! Don't eat it without me! Wait!
ああー！待ってー！
Ahhh! Wait for me!
頑張ってね！
Good luck!
え？
Eh?
行っちゃった...「頑張ってね」って。
They left... saying "good luck."
ええー？本当に寂しいじゃん...
Eh? That's so lonely...
あ、でも今日はね、かぷ民のみんながいるよね！
Ah, but today, all the Kapu-min are here!
よし、改めてみんな、
Alright, once again everyone,
こんかぷー！
Konkapu!
魔界の天才ヴァンパイア、夜空メルです！
Underworld's genius vampire, Yozora Mel here!
今日は最後まで楽しんでってください！
Please enjoy until the very end today!
そしてそして、ハッシュタグ夜空メル爆誕2022でいっぱいツイートしてね！
And also, please tweet a lot with the hashtag #夜空メル爆誕2022!
写真もバシャバシャ撮ってください！
Please take lots of photos too!
あとでメル見に行くからな！約束だよ！
Mel will look at them later! It's a promise!
このあとも、まだまだコラボとかソロ曲とかたくさん続くので、ぜひぜひ最後まで楽しんでってください！
After this, we still have collabs, solo songs, and more, so please enjoy to the end!
よし！それじゃあ！
Alright! Well then!
このあとも、一緒に楽しんでいくぞー！
Let's keep having fun together!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Take cover! Get down! Stop!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Take cover! Get down! Stop!
戦場へ 征け 征け そして死に物狂いで
To the battlefield! March, march, and fight desperately
命 散らした その覚悟を示せ
Show the resolve of having cast away your life!
耳に聞こえるだろう あの砲声が
You can hear it, can't you? That artillery fire
抵抗する 有象無象を
The resisting rabble...
踏み潰せ 踏み潰せ
...crush them! Crush them!
「諸君、我々の任務は何だ？」
"Gentlemen, what is our mission?"
「殲滅だ！一匹残らずの殲滅だ！」
"Extermination! The extermination of every last one!"
「為すべきことはただ一つ、地獄を作れ！」
"There is only one thing to do: create a living hell!"
弾丸の雨に 撃たれに行くのが
To go run straight into a rain of bullets...
笑止千万 国の為に 立てよ
...is utterly laughable! Stand up for your country!
戦場へ 征け 征け そして死に物狂いで
To the battlefield! March, march, and fight desperately
命 散らした 覚悟を示せよ
Show the resolve of having cast away your life!
忠誠を 遵守を そしてその魂を
Loyalty, compliance, and even your soul...
すべて捧げ 勝ち鬨を挙げよ
...sacrifice it all, and raise a victory cry!
さあ其処に 築いて見せろ
Now, construct right there...
天に届く 死体の山を
...a mountain of corpses reaching to the heavens!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
何処に恐怖が あると言うんだ
Where on earth is there any fear?
見よ、死肉が 花びらのようだ
Look, the dead flesh is like flower petals!
撒き散らせ 撒き散らせ
Scatter them! Scatter them!
戦の傷跡 忘れちゃいないさ
We haven't forgotten the scars of battle
炎の熱も 零れた涙も
Not the heat of the flames, nor the spilled tears
最後の呻きも 濁った瞳も
Not the final groans, nor the glazed-over eyes
嗚呼、それこそを 求めるのだろう
Ah, that is exactly what you desire, isn't it?
憐れみも 請う間もなく 破壊を
Without even time to beg for mercy, bring destruction!
敵はすべて 飼い犬の処境
Every enemy is in the state of a kept dog
絶望と 混乱を かけた正気の世界は
A sane world wagered on despair and confusion...
地獄よりも 楽園のようだ
...is more like a paradise than hell!
その四肢は 踊る為に
Those limbs are meant for dancing,
踊り狂う為 有るのだろう
...for dancing in a frenzy!
「人間に価値などない 価値無き者同士の争いに」
"Humans have no value, in this conflict between worthless beings..."
「命の徒花を咲かせてみせろ！」
"...let the non-bearing flowers of life bloom!"
法律も 秩序でも
Whether laws or order,
狂った奴が 創ってる
...they are created by the mad
まさに笑劇
Indeed a farce!
不条理だらけの
Filled with nothing but absurdity,
起承転結
...the introduction, development, twist, and conclusion!
戦場へ 征け 征け そして死に物狂いで
To the battlefield! March, march, and fight desperately
命 散らした 覚悟を示せよ
Show the resolve of having cast away your life!
忠誠を 遵守を そしてその魂を
Loyalty, compliance, and even your soul...
すべて捧げ 勝ち鬨を挙げよ
...sacrifice it all, and raise a victory cry!
さあ其処に 築いて見せろ
Now, construct right there...
天に届く 死体の山に
...onto a mountain of corpses reaching to the heavens...
木霊する 憎しみさえ
...even the echoing hatred...
掻き消す 爆発を
...will be drowned out by the explosion!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Take cover! Get down! Halt!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Take cover! Get down! Halt!
メル先輩、誕生日おめでとう！
Mel-senpai, happy birthday!
ラプラスちゃん、ありがとう！
Laplus-chan, thank you!
なかなかカッコよく決まったんじゃない？
That was a pretty cool pose, wasn't it?
まあ、元々カッコいいすけどね。へへっ。
Well, I've always been cool, though. Hehe.
こんなにさ、ちっちゃいのにびっくりした、メル。
I was surprised by how tiny you are.
いや、ちっちゃい、ちっちゃいって何言ってるんすか。ほら！
Hey, what do you mean by "tiny, tiny"? Look!
これ見て。ツノ、ツノ、ツノ。ほら、ほら、これ。
Look at this! Horns, horns, horns! Look, look, this!
ちょっと比べてみよっか？
Shall we compare?
ま、いいですけど。
Well, sure.
ほら、ね？
Look, see?
待って、待ってよ。これ、メルのアホ毛あるから、メルの勝ちだね。
Wait, wait. I have my cowlick, so I win.
メルの勝ち！メルの勝ち！イェーイ！やったー！
Mel wins! Mel wins! Yay! I did it!
いや、いや、いや、いや。
No, no, no, no.
ラプラスちゃんちっちゃいのは可愛いからいいんじゃない？
But you being tiny is cute, so isn't that fine?
え、いや、いや、何か丸め込もうとしてますよね。
Wait, no, you're trying to win me over.
あ、そうだ！
Oh, that's right!
せっかくカッコいい歌歌ったんだしさ、二人でちょっとカッコいい決めポーズとらん？
Since we sang a cool song, why don't we do a cool signature pose?
おお、いいっすね！やろ、やろ。
Oh, sounds good! Let's do it, let's do it.
行くぞ、人間たち！バッチリスショ撮るのだぞ。
Here we go, humans! Make sure to take a good screenshot.
お,撮るのだぞ。
Oh, take screenshots.
おし、じゃあ、まずは、そうだなぁ。
Alright, so first, let's see.
片手を、手をパーにして、
With one hand, make a palm...
そう、そう、そう、突き出す感じ。
Yes, yes, yes, thrusting it forward like this.
おお、いいじゃないっすか。
Oh, that's pretty good.
必殺技みたいな、は！
Like a special move, ha!
わ、カッコよくない？
Wow, doesn't that look cool?
刮目せよ。
Feast your eyes on us.
いいじゃん。
Looking good.
ラプメル。
Lapu-Mel.
いいね。
Nice.
他のやろう。次いいよ。
Let's do another one. Next is fine.
じゃあ、次は腕組みして、
Next, cross your arms,
背中合わせで。
and stand back-to-back.
お、いいね。少年漫画王道の...
Oh, nice. Like a classic shonen manga...
待って、待って。
Wait, wait.
めっちゃ近い。
We're too close.
あ、すいません。
Oh, sorry.
邪魔。
You're in the way.
ツノ邪魔、メル写んない。
Your horns are in the way, I can't be seen.
メル写ってない。
I'm not in the frame.
メルさん、ちょっと服がエロいんで、
Mel-san, your outfit is a bit too sexy,
ヴァンパイアにならないようにね。
so try not to act like a vampire.
気をつけないといけないっすよ。我が輩の気遣いね、これ。ほら、見て。
You've got to be careful. This is my consideration for you. Look.
はあ？どきなさい、いいから！
Huh? Just move aside already!
いや、何で、何で。
No, why, why?
このツノ、いいから、痛い！
Just move these horns! Ouch!
邪魔、どきなさい！
They're in the way, move aside!
こら、メルさん、ちょっと！
Hey, Mel-san, wait!
こちら、幸福安心委員会です。
[Title: This is the Happiness Assurance Committee]
どうして
Why is it
みんなが幸せなの？
that everyone is happy?
この世界のことを
I want to hear, I want to know
聞きたいって 知りたいって
more about this world.
水辺の公園で
In the park by the water,
みんなが耳を澄ませて
everyone strains their ears.
わくわくするね ねえ
It's so exciting, right?
オンディーヌ？
Hey, Ondine?
はい、はい！
Yes, yes!
さあさあ、みなさん、教えてあげまーす！
Now then, everyone, I'll tell you!
みんなが気になっていること
All the things you're curious about,
疑問に思っていること
all the questions you have...
ぜーんぶ、教えてあげまーす！
I'll tell you absolutely everything!
えー、みなさんが幸福なのは義務なんです。
Now, it is your duty to be happy.
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It is your duty, you know?
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
我々、幸福安心委員会は
We, the Happiness Assurance Committee,
みなさまの幸せを願い、そして支えます。
wish for and support your happiness.
幸福なのは義務なんです！
Being happy is a duty!
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It's a duty, you know?
幸福なのは義務なんです！
Being happy is a duty!
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It's a duty, you know?
ですから、安心して義務を果たしなさい！
So rest assured, and fulfill your duty!
みなさまの幸せが、我々の幸せ。
Your happiness is our happiness.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's a duty, you know?
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
幸せじゃないなら...
If you aren't happy...
絞首 斬首 銃殺 釜茹で 溺死 電気
Hanging, decapitation, firing squad, boiling, drowning, electrocution,
火炙り 生埋め 薬殺 石打ち 鋸 磔
burning at the stake, live burial, lethal injection, stoning, sawing, crucifixion...
好きなのを選んでね。
Choose whichever you like!
はい、はい！
Yes, yes!
さあさあ、みなさん、幸せだけが満ちてまーす！
Now then, everyone, only happiness fills this place!
不安とか不満、何ひとつないでしょう？
There's not a single worry or complaint, right?
恐いわ、恐いわ、
It's scary, it's scary,
幸せすぎて恐いわ。
I'm so happy it's scary.
ほんとに
Is everyone...
みんなが幸せなの？
...truly happy?
この世界の外
"I want to go outside this world,"
行きたいって、逃げたいって
"I want to escape," they said.
水辺の公園で
At the park by the water,
みんなが耳を塞いで
everyone covered their ears
ビクビクしてた
and trembled in fear.
ねえ、ウンディーネ？
Hey, Undine?
ハイハーイ！
Hi-hi!
さあさあ、みなさん 死にましたー！
Well now, everyone, they died!
オンディーヌをふった騎士は死にました！
The knight who rejected Ondine has died!
葬儀に出るなら向こうに並べ！
If you're attending the funeral, line up over there!
それ以外は幸せに暮らせ！
Otherwise, live happily!
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is your duty.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, you know?
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is your duty.
幸せですか？ 義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's your duty, you know?
義務なんです
It's a duty.
義務ですよ？
It's your duty, you know?
義務なんです
It's a duty.
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is your duty.
義務なんです
It's a duty.
義務ですよ？
It's your duty, you know?
義務なんです
It's a duty.
幸せじゃないなら
If you're not happy...
死ね
die.
一緒に怒られて
Getting scolded together,
一緒に大きくなって
growing up together,
一緒に涙して
crying together,
その分もっと笑った
and laughing even more.
仲良しの姉妹で
We were close sisters,
隠し事はなかった
we had no secrets.
好きな人の話
Talking about our crushes,
いつか聞きたいかも
I hope to hear yours someday.
突然どうしたの？
What's with this all of a sudden?
うちら仲良しだけど
We are close, but...
大人になるほどね
The more we grow up, the more...
秘密増えちゃっていいの！
...it's okay to have more secrets!
予想は芸能関係
My guess is someone in show business!
爽やかな王子様？
A refreshing prince-type?
どうしよう... 全然違う
Oh no... he's totally different.
だけどいいの！王子様
But that's okay! He's my prince.
ぶりっ子して
Act cute,
ほっぺつけて
press our cheeks together,
ポーズ決めて
strike a pose,
アップしよう
and upload it!
大好きだよ
I love you!
見つめ合って
Look at each other,
可愛いねって
and say we're cute!
苦手なこと
Things we're bad at,
得意なこと
things we're good at,
好みだとか
or our preferences—
それぞれじゃん？
we're different, right?
嫌いだよ
I hate you!
ケンカしても
Even if we fight,
ずっと一緒だよね
we'll be together forever, right?
ルリレラ
Ru-ri-re-ra!
こちらの方ですが
As for this person here,
お付き合いをしてます
we are dating!
イメージ真逆でも
Even if we are polar opposites,
ちゃんと仲良くしてね
please get along with him!
取られたくないから
I didn't want him taken away,
少し拗ねてみたけど
so I was a little sulky...
ほんと楽しそうで
But you look so happy,
私も嬉しくなった
it made me happy too!
気になる人とかいないの？
Don't you have anyone you like?
お姉ちゃんに教えて
Tell your big sister!
決めたの 恋愛は禁止
I've decided! Love is forbidden!
今はダメ 夢のため
Not right now, for my dream's sake!
キメ顔して
Make a cool face,
ウインクして
wink,
照れ隠して
hide your blushing,
アップしよう
and upload it!
大好きだよ
I love you!
見つめ合って
Look at each other,
可愛いねって
and say we're cute!
似ているとこ
Things we have in common,
似てないとこ
things we don't,
趣味だとか
or our hobbies—
それぞれじゃん？
we're different, right?
嫌いだよ
I hate you!
仲直りも
Making up...
きっとすぐできる
...will surely be easy!
ルリレラ
Ru-ri-re-ra!
一つ屋根の下で
Under one roof,
明日も騒ごう
let's have fun tomorrow too!
Foo! Yeah!
ぶりっ子して
Act cute,
ほっぺつけて
touch cheeks,
ポーズ決めて
strike a pose,
アップしよう
and post it!
大好きだよ
I love you,
見つめ合って
let's gaze at each other,
可愛いね
so cute!
苦手なこと
Things we're bad at,
得意なこと
things we're good at,
好みだとか
and our preferences,
それぞれじゃん？
aren't they all different?
嫌いだよ
Even if I hate it,
even if I hate it,
喧嘩しても
and we fight...
ずっと一緒だよね
We'll always be together, right?
ルルリラ
Rululila!
Yeah! Yay!
Mel-senpai, happy birthday!
おめりあ、thank you! Thank you, thank you!
Omeria, thank you! Thank you, thank you!
一緒に歌って踊れて楽しかったよ！
It was so fun singing and dancing together!
うん、メルも！
Yeah, Mel too!
あのねあのね、今日はさ、メルの誕生日だから、何かご褒美ちょうだい！プリーズ！
You know, you know, today is Mel's birthday, so give me a reward! Please!
え？何、何がいいかな？
Eh? What, what would you like?
あ、うーん、じゃあ、please kiss me!
Ah, hmmm, then, please kiss me!
Oh, Mel-senpai!
わー！大好き！
Wow! I love you!
大好き！
I love you!
I love Amelia! うれしい！
I love Amelia! I'm so happy!
これからも一緒に遊んでください！
Please hang out with me in the future too!
Of course, Amelia! I wanted to do some things with you.
アメリアとやりたいことある！
There is something I want to do with Amelia!
何、何？
What, what is it?
えっとね、3rd Fesで踊ってたダンスが可愛かったから、一緒にやりたい！
You see, the dance you did at the 3rd Fes was so cute, I want to do it together!
おー、いい？ いいよ！
Oh, really? Sure!
プルプル、プルプル...せーの！
Purupuru, purupuru... Ready, set...
プルプル... プルプル...
Purupuru... purupuru...
Yay! Yay!
ダンス可愛かったよ！
The dance was so cute!
ありがとう、thank you!
Thank you, thank you!
Everyone, take lots of pictures, okay?
いっぱい撮った？ 写真撮った？
Did you take a lot? Did you take photos?
ちょっとアメリア、近くに...カモ、カモ！ あ、ぎゅー！
Amelia, get a little closer... Come on, come on! Ah, squeeze!
Cheese! Hehe, gyu, cheese!
Cheese! Hehe, squeeze, cheese!
Cute! Cute! We are cute!
メル先輩、本当に可愛い、めちゃ可愛い！ アメリアも可愛いよ！
Mel-senpai, you're really cute, super cute! Amelia, you're cute too!
Nice sister! Nice sister!
また遊ぼうね！
Let's play again!
Mel-senpai, これからもよろしくね！
Mel-senpai, let's keep working together!
よろしくね！
Looking forward to it!
また遊びましょう！
Let's play again!
これからもアメルをよろしく！ Bye-bye!
Please continue to support Amel! Bye-bye!
どうもこんにちは君の分身です
Hello, how do you do? I am your alter ego.
何の冗談か目を擦ってみる
Thinking it's some joke, I rub my eyes.
影が二つ伸びて そしてまた幕が上がる
Two shadows stretch out, and then the curtain rises once again.
もう一人自分がいたらなぁって言いました
You said, "I wish there was another me."
そんな真摯な願いが僕を呼んだのさ
And that earnest wish called out to me.
そりゃ願ったり叶ったりだ 難観苦難苦渋 全ての代行者
Well, it's a dream come true. Hardship, distress, bitterness... I'll act on your behalf for all of it.
過程はいいから結果を下さい 無意味で無意義な代償
Never mind the process, just give me results. A meaningless, useless compensation.
ねぇこんな事より大事な事があるんだ
Hey, there's something more important than this.
いいだろう？
Isn't that right?
やりますやります何でもやります 僕は君の分身です
I'll do it, I'll do it, I'll do whatever it takes. I am your alter ego.
含み笑いで救世主は言う
With a smirk, the savior says...
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you?
嗚呼混濁と交差して僕は誰？
Ah, intersecting with chaos, who am I?
ねぇ有りもしない ＃０ と証明の根拠なんて何処にも
Hey, there's no such thing as #0, nor any proof of existence anywhere.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は誰は君？
Dear Doppelganger, who is who? Is it you?
蝕まれた存在に世界は気付かないね
The world doesn't notice a corrupted existence, does it?
鳴り止まない醒めない奇跡の輪廻が 狂った正解を染め上げてルンパッパ
The unending, unawakening cycle of miracles colors the mad correct answer—rum-pa-pa!
どうも様子がおかしい月曜日
Somehow things seem strange on this Monday.
一つ二つ崩れゆく辻褄が
One by one, the consistency begins to crumble.
僕を排斥する お前は一体誰だ？
Excluding me, who on earth are you?
誰だと
Who are you?
ちょっと待って 知らぬ知らぬ存ぜぬ 知らない言葉
Wait, "I don't know, I don't know, I don't know" are unfamiliar words.
そうやって紡ぐ マニュアル 影は溶けゆく
Spinning it like that, a manual, the shadow dissolves.
僕はなんなんだろうね
What am I, I wonder?
ねえ どうか存在を返して
Hey, please return my existence.
お生憎様だがこっちはこっちで随分心地が良くて もうあなたの居場所はここには無いこと分かってるんでしょ
I'm sorry, but things are quite comfortable on my end. You already know there's no place for you here anymore, right?
ねえ 奪われたんなら奪えばいいだろ 今度はお前の番だから
If it was stolen from you, then why don't you steal it back? Since next is your turn.
含み笑いで 侵略者（インベーダー）は言う
With a chuckle, the invader says:
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰
"Dear Doppelganger, who... who are you?"
嗚呼 混濁と交差して僕は誰
"Ah, intersecting with confusion, who am I?"
もうさあそれこそ僕なんだ 命の椅子は一つだけ
"See, that's exactly who I am. There's only one seat of life."
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は君 誰は僕
"Dear Doppelganger, which one is you and which one is me?"
零れ落ちた一粒の 乾きを果たす為に
To quench the thirst of a single spilled drop...
誰でもいい何でもいい 器を僕にください
...anyone will do, anything will do, please give me a vessel.
狂った正解が染め上げているんだ
A crazy correct answer is dyeing it all.
それはずっと続く ヒトの業の連鎖
That is the chain of human karma that goes on forever.
委ね合って許し合って満たされ往く
Entrusting each other, forgiving each other, becoming fulfilled.
欠けたピース 価値観のペイン 羨望 嫉妬 愛も
Missing pieces, the pain of values, envy, jealousy, and love too.
託し合って生まれ変わる イニシエーション
Entrusting each other, reborn in an initiation.
僕のほうがちゃんと君を生きてるから
Because I'm living your life better than you are.
君も次の誰かちゃんと救わなくちゃ
You also have to properly save the next someone.
もう分かってるなら何をすればいいかさあ
If you already know, come on, what should we do?
どうか誰か僕に奇跡をくれよ
Please, someone, grant me a miracle.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は 君は誰
Dear Doppelganger, who... who are you?
嗚呼 混濁と交差して僕は誰
Ah, intersecting with confusion, who am I?
もう止まらない 戻れない どうもこんにちは 君の分身です
Can't stop anymore, can't go back. Hello there, I'm your alter ego.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー それは それは僕
Dear Doppelganger, that... that is me.
居場所奪われた存在の
The existence whose place was stolen...
騒め正解が潜む
...a bustling correct answer lies inside.
もう止まらない 止められない 奇跡の輪廻が
Can't stop anymore, can't be stopped, the miracle cycle of reincarnation...
狂った正解を染め上げていく さあ 幕引きに寄るんだ
...is dyeing the crazy correct answer. Come, let's head towards the curtain call.
どうもこんにちは 君の分身です
“Hello there, I'm your alter ego.”
どうだっていい言を 嘘って吐いて戻れない
I spout nonsense as lies and now there's no turning back.
時効なんてやってこない 奪ったように奪われて
There's no statute of limitations; I'm stolen from just as I stole.
今日だって叶わない 思ったように騙せない
Even today, it won't come true; I can't deceive them as I wanted.
腐っている僕には 腐ったものが理解らない
For a rotten person like me, I can't even recognize rotten things.
おいで
Come on...
ココまで
...over here,
避けて
avoid me.
「隠して仕舞ったんだ」
“I ended up hiding it away.”
メーデー 僕と判っても もう抱き締めなくて易々んだよ<
Mayday! Even if you realize it's me, you don't have to hold me tight anymore.
メーデー 僕が解ったら もう一度嘲笑ってくれるかな
Mayday! If you understand me, would you laugh at me once more?
マボロシだって知るんだよ
I know it's just an illusion.
嘘憑きだって知るんだよ ねえ
I know I'm just a liar, you know?
NOだって言う筋が キョドってYESを声に出す
Even though I have no reason to say NO, I suspiciously voice a YES.
後悔の脆弱は 騙したほうが正義なの
In the vulnerability of regret, is deceiving others the ultimate justice?
卑怯だって構わない 祈っておいてそれはない
I don't care if it's cowardly. You prayed for it, so don't say that.
飾っていた饒舌が 墓穴を掘って焼ける様
The eloquence I decorated myself with digs its own grave and burns away.
追い詰めて
Cornering me...
どこまで
...how far will you go?
灰色
Gray...
被害者ヅラしたって
...even if you act like the victim.
メーデー 僕を叱ってよ 正直者が夢見たいなら
Mayday! Scold me, if an honest person wants to dream.
メーデー 僕を裁いてよ 最後まで甘えてしまうのは
Mayday! Judge me, because being spoiled until the very end...
亡霊だって知るんだよ
...tells me that I'm just a ghost.
空白だって知るんだよ ねえ
I know it's just a blank space, you know?
足りないものを望んだら
If I wish for what is lacking,
僕じゃない僕が
a "me" that isn't me...
出会ったよ
I met you...
それでも前に進んだの
Even so, I kept moving forward.
クラクラしちゃうよもう
I'm already feeling so dizzy.
足りない僕を愛してよ EGOのままが僕を育てたから
Love me, incomplete as I am, since this ego is what raised me.
君には僕が見えるかな 孤独なピエロが...
Can you see me, a lonely clown?
メーデー 僕と判っても もう抱き締めなくていいんだよ
Mayday! Even if you realize it's me, you don't have to hold me close anymore.
メーデー 僕が解ったら もう一度笑ってくれるかな
Mayday! If you figure me out, will you smile for me once more?
メーデー 僕を叱ってよ 正直者が夢見たいなら
Mayday! Go ahead and scold me, if an honest person wants to dream.
メーデー 僕を裁いてよ 最後まで甘えてしまうのは
Mayday! Go ahead and judge me, because I end up depending on you till the very end.
メーデー 僕を暴いてよ 正直者はこの世界から
Mayday! Go ahead and expose me, from an honest person in this world.
メーデー 僕と踊ってよ 最初からいないと判ってた
Mayday! Come and dance with me, when I knew from the start I didn't exist.
マボロシだって知るんだよ
I know it's just an illusion.
嘘憑きだって知るんだよ Nus
I know I'm just a liar.
空白だって知るんだよ
I know it's just a void.
どうだっていいこと...
For things that don't even matter...
どうだっていいことを
Things that don't even matter...
嘘って吐いて戻れない
I spit out lies and now I can't go back.
時効なんてやってこない
No statute of limitations will ever come.
奪ったように奪われて
Getting snatched away just as I had stolen.
わー！メル先輩！お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Wow! Mel-senpai! Happy birthday!
わー！ありがとう、こよちゃん！
Wow! Thank you, Koyo-chan!
いや、本当に一緒に歌えて嬉しいです、呼んでいただき！
I'm really happy we could sing together, thank you for inviting me!
うわー！ありがとうございます！
Uwah! Thank you so much!
なんですけど、ちょっとこより、メル先輩にこの機会にちょっと聞きたいことがあるんですが…
But you see, Koyori has something she wants to ask Mel-senpai on this occasion...
何？
What is it?
なんかこよりとは、ワンナイトとかツーナイトとか、つま、言ってたじゃないですか？
I mean, you said things like "one night" or "two nights" with Koyori, didn't you?
あー、ね。言ってたね、そんなこと。
Ah, right. I did say that.
そ、そこのところ、どうなんですか？結局こよのことどう思ってるんですか？
So, how is it really? What do you actually think of Koyo?
え？
Eh?
あー、いや、こより。何言ってんだ。もう初めてのお風呂も、その他もろもろもろ、こよりが初めてなんだぜ？
Ah, well, Koyori... What are you talking about? Our first bath together, and all those other things... Koyori was my first for everything.
もうそれってどういう意味か、分かるよな？
You know what that means, right?
えっ、あ、ちょ、急にイケボ、ずるい！
Eh, ah, wait, using a handsome voice all of a sudden is unfair!
よし。 // うわ、なんか今、心の声が聞こえた気がするけど…
There. // Whoa, I feel like I just heard your inner voice...
あ、いや、こよちゃん、こよちゃん、そう、そうだそうだ。
Ah, no, Koyo-chan, Koyo-chan, yes, that's right.
せっかくさ、そりコラボなんだから、一緒に何か、はい、写真撮ろうよ！
Since this is our collab, let's take a photo together!
はい！あ、撮り、なんか流された気がするけど、はい！
Yes! Ah, taking... I feel like I was just brushed off, but okay!
はい！撮りましょう！撮りましょう！ // 撮りましょう！やったー！
Yes! Let's take it! Let's take it! // Let's take it! Yay!
何撮ろうかな？ // どうしましょうか？
What pose should we do? // What should we do?
じゃあ、名探偵メルこよだから、我らね。
Well, since we're Great Detectives Mel-Koyo...
それっぽいポーズ撮らん？ // あ、いいですね！
How about we do a fitting pose? // Oh, that sounds great!
そしたら、じゃあ、あれかな？
Then, maybe that one?
あれだね！あれだね、きっと！ // 一致してるな。
That one! That one, for sure! // We're on the same page.
じゃ、背中合わせにして、かっこよく決めよう！ // はい、はい！
Then let's go back-to-back and look cool! // Yes, yes!
オッケーです！ // 行くよ？ // はい！
Okay! // Ready? // Yes!
せーの、真実は、いつも…
One, two, the truth is always...
ひとつ！
...one!
お、かっこいい！ // かっこいい！
Oh, cool! // Cool!
決まったんじゃない？みんなパシャパシャ撮ってね！
Didn't we nail it? Everyone, take lots of screenshots!
撮ってください！
Please take pictures!
いいね、いいね。これは謎が解けるぞ。
Nice, nice. This will definitely solve the mystery.
これはもう名探偵の目も迷いじゃなくて、名前の何になりそうですね。
Now the 'Me' in 'Great Detective' will stand for 'reputation' instead of 'hesitation'!
そうだそうだ！
Exactly, exactly!
じゃあ、次は… // はい！なんか、可愛いポーズとか？
Then, next is... // Yes! Maybe a cute pose?
あの、いいですか？あの… // 何何？
Um, is it okay? Um... // What, what?
可愛いで、あの、ちゃんとこよりとは、もうワンナイトとか言わせないために…
With "cute"... to make sure no one ever calls us a "one-night stand" again...
なんか、ぎゅーって感じの証拠写真撮らせてもらっていいですか？
Can we take a hugging photo as proof?
お！
Oh!
あ、流された感じしたんで。
Ah, since I felt brushed off earlier.
じゃ、え、いいですか？ぎゅーってして。
Then, is it okay? Let's hug.
せーの、ぎゅー！やったー！
One, two, squeeze! Yay!
ぎゅー！
Huuug!
あ、恥ずかしい！恥ずかしい！
Ah, embarrassing! This is embarrassing!
あ、ドキドキが伝わってくる気がする！
Ah, I feel like I can feel your heartbeat!
ぎゅーは初めてだよ、こよちゃんと。
Hugging like this is a first with you, Koyo-chan.
あ、こよも！
Ah, Koyo too!
撮られてる、みんなに。 // ドキドキ。
We're being photographed by everyone. // Heart pounding.
大勢に見守られて撮られている。
We're being watched and photographed by so many people.
ちょっと、なんかちょっと絵的に… // 何考えてるの、もう！
Wait, the layout of this picture is a bit... // What on earth are you thinking?!
何でもないです！何でもないです！
Nothing! It's nothing!
こよちゃん、今日は本当にありがとう。
Koyo-chan, thank you so much for today.
一緒に歌えて、メルもめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったよ！
I was super happy to sing together too!
こよのほうこそです！
Me too!
これからもラブラブしていきましょうね！
Let's keep being lovey-dovey in the future too!
していこうね！
Let's do that!
こんこよー！こんかぷー！
Konkoyo! Konkapu!
HANAJI
[Song: HANAJI]
ハッとしたり
Being startled,
ゾッとしたり ワクワク
shivering, and getting excited!
キュンときてジャン
Squeezing my heart, bang!
ツンときてジャン
Acting cold, bang!
ハートはハイテンション
My heart is in high tension!
運命の恋を 探しにきたけど
I came here searching for a fated love, but
目移り腕まくり
my eyes wander as I roll up my sleeves.
微熱少女の鼻血が 満開全開
A slightly feverish girl's nosebleed is in full bloom and wide open!
幸せ咲き誇る
Happiness blooms in full glory.
あの子の秘密を 分けあう奴に
To the one who shares that girl's secrets,
お熱気味ですの
I'm feeling a little bit of a fever.
アイツに会うと カミングアウト
When I meet them, I'm coming out.
責められ いじられ やめて やめて あ〜 は〜
Accused and teased, "stop it, stop it, ah, ha!"
追い詰められて 振り回されて
Cornered and swung around,
アメとムチ 炸裂
the carrot and the stick explode!
逃げたいくらい いじめられちゃう
Teased so much that I want to run away,
だけど変わってみたいの
but I want to try changing.
ハッとしたり
Being startled,
ゾッとしたり
shivering,
ハッとしたり ワクワク
and getting excited!
キュンときてジャン
Squeezing my heart, bang!
ツンときてジャン
Acting cold, bang!
ハートはハイテンション
My heart is in high tension!
そわそわ窓辺 デコボコ丁度ね
Fidgeting by the window, the unevenness is just right,
気合も浮きまくり
and my enthusiasm is floating away.
ハラハラちょうだい 虫酸は走り
Give me thrills, my skin is crawling,
されても乗るばかり
but even so, I'll just go along with it.
退治はしないの 心のハントで
I won't exterminate you, with my heart's hunt
ズバッと愛しとくわ
I'll love you in one clean shot!
ピクピク合うと カミングアウト
Twitching, when I meet you, I'm coming out,
ディープに ディープに 埋もれていくの
deeply, deeply getting buried in, ah, ha!
恵みを受けてきたり 恵みは降りて
Receiving blessings, they rain down,
もう手遅れの兆しなの
it's already a sign of being too late.
逆らっていても 罵られても
Even if I defy, even if I'm abused,
だけど星にうつりちゃう
but my heart drifts to the stars.
あの子の秘密を 分けあう奴に
To the one who shares that girl's secrets,
お熱気味ですの
I'm feeling a little bit of a fever.
アイツに会うと カミングアウト
When I meet them, I'm coming out.
責められ いじられ やめて やめて あ〜 は〜
Accused and teased, "stop it, stop it, ah, ha!"
追い詰められて 振り回されて
Cornered and swung around,
アメとムチ 炸裂
the carrot and the stick explode!
逃げたいくらい いじめられちゃう
Teased so much that I want to run away,
だけど変わってみたいの
but I want to try changing.
ゾッとしたり
Shivering,
ハッとしたり
being startled,
ハッとしたり ワクワク
being startled, and getting excited!
キュンときてジャン
Squeezing my heart, bang!
ツンときてジャン
Acting cold, bang!
ハートはハイテンション
My heart is in high tension!
はーい！というわけで、メルちゃん！
Okay! And with that, Mel-chan!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
わー！マリンちゃんありがとー！うれしい！
Wow! Thank you, Marine-chan! I'm so happy!
やったー！やったー！
Hooray! Hooray!
あ、ちょうどさ、去年の誕生日ライブにもマリン来てくれたよね？
Ah, and you know, Marine also came to my birthday live last year, right?
そうだよ、メルちゃん！
That's right, Mel-chan!
さ、え、もしかして、マリンのこと好き？
Wait, could it be... do you like Marine?
えっ？
Eh?
おっ、引いてんじゃないよ！
Hey, don't look so repulsed!
でもまあ、メルね、
But well, for me,
マリンともっと遊びたいと思ってるよ！
I want to play more with Marine!
おお！
Oh!
うん！人間界にも最近来たばかりだし、
Yeah! Since I just recently came to the human world,
今度はさ、うちに来ないかい？マリン！
next time, why don't you come to my place, Marine?
え、メルちゃんち、え、いったい何されるの？
Eh!? Mel-chan's house? What on earth are you going to do to me?
いったい何をされるの？
What are you going to do to me?!
え、こないだの続きに決まってるでしょ？
Eh? The continuation of last time, of course!
な、なんすか、続き！こないだこないと、ちょっと過去すぎて忘れてんだけど、なんか、なんかあったっけ？
W-What do you mean, continuation?! Last time... that was too long ago, I forgot. Did something happen?
マリン、すぐ誘っといて、寝たふりしたんだ！
Marine, you invited me over and then immediately pretended to sleep!
えっ？さ、誘ったって、メルちゃんちょっと自意識過剰だな、別に誘ってないんだけど。
Eh?! I invited you? Mel-chan, you're a bit self-conscious. I didn't really invite you.
誘ったよ！
You did!
誘ったよ！チャットしたよ、すぐに！秒で来てたじゃん！
You did invite me! You messaged me immediately, you replied in seconds!
おお！
Oh!
ま、ちょっと、ちょっと忘れてたけど、今度はね、メルちゃんち、行こうかな！
Well, I forgot a bit, but next time, maybe I'll go to Mel-chan's house!
やったー！決まりね！
Yay! It's a promise!
メルちゃん、マジでマリンのこと好きだな、困ったな。
Mel-chan really loves Marine, oh dear.
はいはいはいはい、じゃあ、
Yeah, yeah, sure, sure. Well then,
はいはい、
Sure, sure,
マリン、せっかく1年越しに、ね、2人の3Dライブだから、ポーズ一緒に取ろう！
Marine, since it's our joint 3D live after a whole year, let's strike a pose together!
あ、いいよいいよ、どんなポーズにする？
Ah, sure, sure! What kind of pose should we strike?
そうだなぁ、さっき、なんか曲中だと、なんか…
Let's see... earlier, during the song, we did...
あ、メルが、メルがマリーンになったから
Ah, since Mel became Marine...
ちょっと逆のも見たいかな
I want to see the reverse too.
マリーン攻め？
Marine is dominant?
じゃあちょっと、スーパーダーリン見せるか。いや、でもさ、
Then should I show you my super darling? No, but...
ドS系？ドS系の方がいいのかな？
An S-type? Is an S-type better?
そう。ちょっと、ドSのマリーンのいじめを見たいかな
Yes. I want to see dominant Marine bully me a little.
あ、なるほど。じゃ、ちょっと、メルちゃん、ちょっと歯を食いしばってもらってもいい？
Ah, I see. Then, Mel-chan, could you clench your teeth for a second?
バチーン！あー！
Smack! Ah!
メル、この豚！この豚！
Mel, you pig! You pig!
うひー！
Uhee!
メル、ひざまずきなさい！
Mel, kneel down!
あら、どう？
Oh, how is it?
これ、これが好きです！
This, I like this!
気持ちいいです！
It feels good!
あ、やっぱり好きなんだ。これ気持ちいいのね。
Ah, so you really like it. This feels good, huh?
うひー！
Uhee!
あ、こんな変態とはお友達でいられません！
Ah, I cannot remain friends with such a pervert!
お前も変態だろうが！
You're a pervert too!
バレちゃった。ちょっと、汚い空気になってきたから、
I've been caught. Since the atmosphere is getting dirty...
可愛いポーズとろっか。
Let's do a cute pose.
そうだね、ラストはちょっと可愛く決めましょうか。
That's right, let's strike a cute pose for the end.
２人愛し合ってるってことが完全に判明したから、
Since it's completely clear that we love each other...
ハート作ろっか。
Let's make a heart.
オッケー、ハートね、一緒に。
Okay, a heart, together.
はい、せーの！
Yes, ready, go!
いぇーい！
Yay!
世界で一番おひめさま
World's number one princess
そういう扱い心得てよね
Make sure you know how to treat me like that, okay?
えええええええええええよね
Eeeeeeeeeee, okay?!
ワールドイズマイン
[World is Mine]
その一 いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
Number one: Notice when my hairstyle is different from usual
その二 ちゃんと靴まで見ること いいね？
Number two: Make sure you look all the way down to my shoes, okay?
その三 私の一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Number three: Answer my every word with three words of reply
わかったら右手がお留守なのを何とかして！
If you understand, do something about my empty right hand!
別にわがままなんて言っていないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
キミに心から思ってほしいの「かわいい」って
I just want you to think from the bottom of your heart that I'm cute
世界で一番おひめさま
World's number one princess,
気がついて ねえねえ 待たせるなんて論外よ
Notice me, hey, hey... Making me wait is out of the question
私を誰だと思っているの？
Who do you think I am?
もう なんだか甘いものが食べたい！
Geez, I really want to eat something sweet!
いますぐによ
Right now!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You must have mistaken them for cuteness
文句は許しませんの
I won't tolerate any complaints
あのね 私の話ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっと...
Hey, are you listening to what I'm saying? Hey...
あ、それとね 白いお馬さん 決まってるでしょ？
Oh, and also, a white horse. It's obvious, right?
迎えに来て
Come pick me up
わかったらかしづいて 手を取って「おひめさま」って
If you understand, bow down, take my hand and call me "princess"
別にわがままなんて言っていないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything,
でもね 少しくらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ
But you know, it's okay to scold me just a little bit
世界で私だけのおうじさま
The world's only prince for me,
気がついて ほらほら おててが空いてます
Notice me, look, look... My hand is empty
無口でぶ愛想なおうじさま
A quiet, unsociable prince,
もう どうして？
Geez, why?
気がついてよ早く
Notice me quickly!
絶対キミはわかってない
You absolutely don't understand,
わかってないわ...
you just don't get it...
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
A strawberry shortcake,
こだわりたまごの とろけるプリン
melting pudding made with select eggs...
みんな みんな 我慢します// I'll endure them all
I'll endure them all, so
わがままな子だと思わないで
please don't think I'm a selfish girl
私だってやればできるもん
I can do it if I try.
あとで後悔するわよ
You'll regret this later!
当然です！だって私は
Of course! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
The world's number one princess.
ちゃんと見ててよね
Watch me closely, okay?
どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Or I might go away somewhere.
ふいに抱きしめられた
Suddenly, I was embraced...
急にそんな えっ？
So out of nowhere, huh?
…なるわよ
…it will be too late.
お耳とお目目 そっちじゃないの
Your ears and eyes, not over there!
こっちのが危ないわよ
Look over here, it's dangerous!
みんなー！
Everyone!
こんこぷー！
Konkopu!
ライブ楽しんでる？
Are you enjoying the live show?
いっぱい歌ったねー
I sang a lot, didn't I?
めちゃくちゃ楽しんでるよ、メルは！
I'm having so much fun, I am!
今年のハロウィンも、誕生日も
This year's Halloween and my birthday too...
みんなのおかげで
...thanks to everyone...
めっちゃ楽しい！ありがとう！
are super fun! Thank you!
でね、今回のステージ、もう気づいてくれたかな？
By the way, did you notice our stage this time?
今回もね、メル仕様に、なんと！作っていただきましたー！
This time, they made it specially in Mel's theme! Look!
どどん！可愛いでしょ？
Tada! Isn't it cute?
すごいでしょ？
Isn't it amazing?
ねー、めちゃくちゃ可愛い！
Right? It's so incredibly cute!
今日はね、いつもよりも
Today, even more than usual...
すごい告知があります！
I have some huge announcements!
それはこのあと説明するので、ぜひ最後まで聞いてってくだい！
I'll explain them in a moment, so please listen until the end!
まずは！
First of all!
どぅるるるるん！
Drumroll...
夜空メル誕生日記念グッズ2022！
Yozora Mel Birthday Celebration Goods 2022!
どどどどーん！
Tada!
今回も可愛いグッズをいっぱい用意してます！
We have plenty of cute items ready this time as well!
その1！
Number one!
夜空メルバースデーライト ～LEDアクリルスタンドライト～になってます！
The Yozora Mel Birthday Light - LED Acrylic Stand Light!
浅木ゆな先生描き下ろしのイラストだよ！
It features an illustration drawn by Asagi Yuna-sensei!
カッコいいでしょ？なんか
Doesn't it look cool? Like...
いつもは可愛いメルだけど
Mel is usually cute...
今回はカッコ可愛いメルに描いていただきました！
but this time, she drew me looking cool and cute!
お部屋でね、ぜひ使ってください！
Please make sure to display it in your room!
そして、その2！
And then, number two!
魔界の晩餐会グラス！
The Underworld Banquet Glass!
これはワイングラスです！
This is a wine glass!
これメルずっと作りたかったんだよね！
I've wanted to make this for the longest time!
メルはアセロラジュースを入れてね、飲むつもりだけど
I'm planning to fill it with acerola juice, but...
みんなはワインとか、ぶどうジュースとか
everyone else can pour wine or grape juice in it...
入れてね、ぜひこうやってね、ルネッサンスってね、飲んでください！
...and toast with a "Renaissance" as you drink!
いっぱい使ってね！
Please use it a lot!
その3！
Number three!
メルの魔導書パスケース！
Mel's Grimoire Pass Case!
これはパスケースになってます！
This is a pass case!
日常でぜひいっぱい使ってほしいな！
I hope you'll use it every day!
実はね、この本の柄...
Actually, the design of this book...
今後ね、メルの配信や歌ってみたなどで今後出てくる予定が...
...is scheduled to appear in Mel's future streams and cover songs!
あります！
Yes, it is!
何かっていうのは、ちょっと今は内緒なんだけど
As for what it is, it's a secret for now...
その時のお楽しみということで
...so look forward to it when the time comes!
皆さんぜひ先取りでゲットしてほしいな！
But I'd love for everyone to get it ahead of time!
そして、次がビッグなお知らせ！
And next up is some big news!
その4！
Number four!
ててーん！
Tada!
夜空メル 1stアルバム『Twinkle Star Magic☆』です！
Yozora Mel's 1st Album, "Twinkle Star Magic☆"!
これはぜひゲットしてほしい、もう一番ゲットしてほしいやつ！
I absolutely want you to get this, it's the one I want you to get the most!
カッコいい曲からね、可愛い曲、しっとり曲などなどいっぱい詰め込みました！
We packed it with cool songs, cute songs, mellow songs, and much more!
色んなメルを知ってほしいなと思って
I wanted you to see all different sides of Mel...
たくさん詰め込んだので、ぜひ聞いてほしいです！
...so I put a lot into it. Please check it out!
全部でなんと、どぅん、11曲あります！
In total, there are actually eleven songs!
メルね、5ヶ月連続でオリ曲リリースしてたんですけど
I had been releasing original songs for five consecutive months...
『かぷっとNight☆Sky』から今までのオリ曲、そしてね
...starting with "Kaputto Night☆Sky", and along with those...
まだ配信されてない曲がなんと5曲も入って
...there are actually five unreleased tracks included!
合計11曲になってます！
Making it eleven tracks in total!
さらに！メルの初めてのオリ曲『かぷっとNight☆Sky』のリミックスバージョンも入っています！
What's more! A remix of my very first original song, "Kaputto Night☆Sky", is also included!
さらにさらに！
And even more!
『デイリー・ダイアリー』の夜空メル歌唱バージョンも保存する
A solo vocal version of "Daily Diary" by Yozora Mel...
入ってます！これはね、メル1人でね、5役
...is also included! For this one, I played five different roles all by myself...
演じて歌いました！
...and sang them!
めっちゃ頑張ったから
I worked incredibly hard on it...
聴いてください！
...so please listen to it!
お姉さんボイスとか少年ボイスとかね保存する
Like, using a mature voice and a young boy voice!
そんな感じで歌ったので
I sang with various voices like that...
聴いてください、よろしくお願いします！保存する
...so please check it out!
今回ね、グッズ全部買ってくれた人には
For those who buy the full set of goods...
今回も特典があります！
...we have some special bonuses this time too!
1つ目は、メルからのラブレターです！
First is a love letter from Mel!
これは初めてかもしれないね
This might be the first time I'm doing this!
その2、ASMRボイス！
And second, an ASMR voice track!
こっちもね、甘々になってるので
This one is super sweet too...
合わせて、全部合わせてね、聞いてみてください！
...so please listen to them all together!
めっちゃ噛んだ！
I got so tongue-tied!
もう歌いまくってさ
I sang so much...
呼吸が...
...that I'm out of breath!
いっぱいぜひゲットしてください！
Please make sure to get them!
ちょっと告知長くなっちゃったけど
The announcements got a bit long...
今日はこのあと
but after this today...
メンバー限定でね、アフターライブ！
we have a members-only after-party live show!
アフターライブやります！
We're doing an after-party live show!
メンバーのみんな...
All of my members...
もっと もっと 一緒に もうちょっとだけ 一緒にいたいなと思って
I wanted to spend just a little more time together with you...
お手紙作ったんだけど メルと一緒にいてくれますか？
I wrote a letter... Will you stay with Mel?
やったー！約束だよ！
Yay! It's a promise, okay?
じゃあ 次は最後の曲になります
Now, the next song will be the last one.
きっともう カプ民のみんななら 合いの手ね バッチリだよね？
I'm sure all of you Kapu-mins have the call-and-response down perfectly, right?
大丈夫だよね？
You'll be fine, right?
知らないよって人いたら まあこのあとね ダウンロードしてください
If anyone doesn't know it, well, please download it after this.
めっちゃいい曲なので
It's an amazing song,
聴いてほしいです
so I want you to hear it.
今日もね 本当に本当にありがとう
Thank you so, so much for today as well,
カプ民のみんな
all of my Kapu-mins!
大大好きだよ！
I love you so much!
かぷっ！
Chomp!
じゃあメル こっちで歌っちゃおう！
Well then, Mel will sing from over here!
かぷうぃん中毒
[Song: Kapuwin Addiction / Lyrics & Composition: Yashikin]
歳の数より 歳の数だけ
More than my age, or exactly my age...
それは節分 お菓子をちょーだい
Wait, that's Setsubun! Please give me candy instead!
おばけ かきわけ 夜を駆けてゆく
Pushing through the ghosts, running through the night...
わたしヴァンパイア
...I am a vampire.
ぱっぱらパンプキンが 踊ってて
The pumpkin is dancing around...
てってれ照れちゃって かわいいな
...and acting so shy. How cute!
ジャック・オー・ランタンくんも お年頃
Even Jack-o'-Lantern is at that age...
ドキドキしてるのわかるから
...where I can tell his heart is beating fast!
近づいて
So come closer...
おーはろーはろー Win-win かぷってしたら
Oh, hello, hello! Win-win! If I take a bite...
おーはろーはろー Win-win るるんるんるん
...Oh, hello, hello! Win-win! Humming along~
はろーはろー Win-win そんな関係
Hello, hello! Win-win! A relationship like that...
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん かぷうぃん
Kapuwin, Kapuwin, Kapuwin...
With you
魔女 フランケン 悪魔 ミイラ ゾンビ
Witches, Frankens, demons, mummies, zombies!
逢魔が時の大御所ぞろい
A gathering of twilight's big shots!
TRICK or TREAT
あー全員まるごと釘付け
Ah, everyone will be totally spellbound!
ワクワクしてるよ いざ Party Night
We're so excited! Now, it's Party Night!
お耳 かぷかぷ お腹 たぷたぷ
Biting on ears, tummy is full...
あなたの成分 たくさんちょーだい
...give me lots of your essence!
気配 かぎわけ 夜を駆けてゆく
Scenting your presence, running through the night...
わたしヴァンパイア
...I am a vampire.
おーはろーはろー Win-win かぷってしたら
Oh, hello, hello! Win-win! If I take a bite...
おーはろーはろー Win-win るるんるんるん
...Oh, hello, hello! Win-win! Humming along~
はろーはろー Win-win そんな関係
Hello, hello! Win-win! A relationship like that...
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん かぷうぃん
Kapuwin, Kapuwin, Kapuwin...
With you
キュートが過ぎちゃって
Being way too cute,
ごめんね！
sorry about that!
ボンキュッボンでセクシーポーズ
With an hourglass figure, strike a sexy pose!
かわいい！
Cute!
あなたの心とカラダに
Into your heart and body...
メル！メル！
Mel! Mel!
魔界の？最強！天才！最強！かわいい！
From the Underworld? Strongest! Genius! Strongest! Cute!
ヴァンパイアって〜？
Who's the vampire?
夜空メル！
Yozora Mel!
ぱっぱらパンプキンは どこにいる
Where is the dancing pumpkin?
とっとこ遠くまで 行っちゃった
It went running far, far away.
ジャック・オー・ランタンくんの 浮気者
Jack-o'-Lantern is such a flirt!
ボコボコにしても 連れて帰る
Even if I have to beat him up, I'll bring him back...
覚悟して
...so prepare yourself!
離れたくないよ
I don't want to leave you.
離さないよ
I won't let you go.
いつまででもきっと 一緒がいいな
I want us to be together forever and ever.
このお祭り 共に過ごそう
Let's spend this festival together.
ハロウィン
Halloween...
おーはろーはろー Win-win かぷってしたら
Oh, hello, hello! Win-win! If I take a bite...
おーはろーはろー Win-win るるんるんるん
...Oh, hello, hello! Win-win! Humming along~
はろーはろー Win-win そんな関係
Hello, hello! Win-win! A relationship like that...
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん かぷうぃん
Kapuwin, Kapuwin, Kapuwin...
With you
かぷうぃん かぷうぃん 中毒
Kapuwin, Kapuwin, Addiction!